#### Contact

51997321610 (Mobile) hassan\_bittencourt@hotmail. com

www.linkedin.com/in/ hassanaboliveira (LinkedIn)

# Top Skills

Java

Apigee API Management Maven

# Languages

Inglês (Full Professional)
Francês (Professional Working)
Espanhol (Limited Working)
Portugais (Native or Bilingual)

#### Certifications

Double degree agreements: What, Why, and How do you make?

Curso HTML5 e CSS3: módulo 1 de 5 [40 HORAS]

Django: templates e boas práticas HTML5 e CSS3 parte 1: A primeira página da Web

MongoDB: validando dados

# Hassan Augusto Bittencourt de Oliveira

Software Engineer | Developer Back-End | Python | Django | NoSQL | SQL |

Nice, Provence-Alpes-Côte d'Azur, France

# Summary

Hello, I am a Mechanical Engineering student and Generalist Engineer from Centrale Marseille, one of the largest engineering schools in France. I am a Python developer at the beginning of my career and committed to learning and improving my programming skills. I have basic knowledge of other programming languages, but I decided to focus on Python for its flexibility, efficiency, and ability to elegantly solve complex problems.

In the last two years, I have been involved in software development activities using Python, Django, Flask, NoSQL, SQL and Linux. I am always looking for new challenges and opportunities to grow professionally. I love working in teams and learning from more experienced colleagues, sharing ideas and solutions. I have interpersonal communication skills and can express my ideas clearly and concisely.

I have already had some experiences in programming projects, and I am excited to put my skills into practice in more challenging and significant projects. I am willing to face new challenges and dedicate myself to achieving high-quality results. I feel that I have a lot to learn, and I hope to grow professionally with new opportunities and challenges.

# Experience

Amadeus Software Engineer Intern April 2024 - Present (2 months) Villeneuve-Loubet, Provence-Alpes-Côte d'Azur, France

Centrale Méditerranée

#### Frontend Developer

September 2022 - March 2024 (1 year 7 months)

Marseille, Provence-Alpes-Côte d'Azur, France

- Corrections and improvements to the ECM Mobility-Online website
- Adding steps on the exchange platform
- Management of the database

#### Trendex

### Data Analyst

June 2023 - September 2023 (4 months)

Ajaccio, Córsega, França

- Developed a data analysis and processing system using Python and MongoDB.
- Utilized the PyMongo library to interact with MongoDB and perform queries and aggregations.
- Implemented filters, projections, and aggregation operations to extract specific information from stored documents.
- Leveraged the pandas and numpy libraries for data manipulation, analysis, and numerical calculations.
- Created scripts to automate tasks such as generating reports and visualizing results.
- Acquired skills in programming, data analysis, and database manipulation.
- Gained a deep understanding of the MongoDB ecosystem and its functionalities.

#### Orni

#### Infrastructure Analyst

March 2022 - September 2022 (7 months)

Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

- Domain registration, creation of development environments.
- DNS Management.
- Supervise system versions and verify that changes can progress from homologation to production.
- Bug fixes on websites (EX: form that didn't send email, pages off, plugin errors, ...).
- Maintenance and malware prevention on the server.
- Performing backups via SSH.
- Communication and task planning.

Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul

1 year 5 months

Scientific Initiation in the Applied Mechanics Group (GMap) August 2021 - December 2021 (5 months)

Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

- Numerical modeling of offshore platforms mooring systems

Scientific Initiation at the Tribology Laboratory (LATRIB) August 2020 - August 2021 (1 year 1 month)

Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

- Static friction assessment
- Characterization of surface topography
- Pin-on-disk test procedure (ASTM G99)
- Tribofilm monitoring
- Evaluation of lubricants
- Evaluation of surface morphology
- Between others

Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul (UFRGS) Monitor | Introduction to Mechanical Engineering August 2019 - December 2019 (5 months)

Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

I helped orient and guide new students to the opportunities available in the course and at the university.

# Education

Ecole Centrale de Marseille

Bachelor's degree, Generalist Engineering (August 2022 - September 2024)

Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul Bachelor's degree, Mechanical Engineering (2019 - 2024)